merge.com.au 2012-12-30

# Privacy Policy | Merge

Bookmark/Search this post with: 

The following Privacy Policy summarizes the various ways that Specialist Media ("SM", "Service Provider," "we" or "our") treats the information you provide while using [www.Merge.com.au](http://www.merge.com.au/) ("Website"). It is our aim to bring you information that is tailored to your individual needs and simultaneously, protect your privacy. 

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. Your use of and/or registration on any aspect of the Website will constitute your agreement to this Privacy Policy. If you cannot agree with the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Website. 

In addition to reviewing this Privacy Policy, please read our User Agreement. Your use of the Website constitutes agreement to its terms and conditions as well. This Privacy Policy may be modified from time to time; the date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page, so check back often. Continued access of the Website by you will constitute your acceptance of any changes or revisions to the Privacy Policy. 

1\. THE TYPE OF INFORMATION THE WEBSITE COLLECTS    
The Website generally collects personally identifying information with your specific knowledge and consent. For instance, when you enter a competition, complete a survey, make a purchase, subscribe to our publication(s), or register for any portion of our services, you are asked to provide information such as your e-mail address, name or phone number. Optional information such as your age or gender may also be requested. 

Our servers may also automatically collect information about your computer when you visit the Website, including without limitation the type of browser software you use, the operating system you are running, the website that referred you, and your Internet Protocol ("IP") address. Your IP address is usually associated with the place from which you enter the Internet, like your Internet Service Provider, your company or your university. 

2\. HOW THE WEBSITE USES INFORMATION PROVIDED BY YOU   
Service Provider uses personally identifying information you supply through the Website to provide you with the service you have requested. For example, if you subscribe to any of our publications, we may use your e-mail address to send you a confirmation notice and your mailing address to send you the publication. Similarly, if you enter an online competition, we will request and use this information to notify you if you are a winner. We may also use the information to communicate with you about new features, products or services, and/or to improve the services that we offer by tailoring them to your needs. 

Unless otherwise specified on the Website, Service Provider may sell or share personally identifying information with our affiliates and with carefully selected companies who we think can offer you services and products of interest to you. If you do not wish to have your personally identifying information shared, write to us at the street address at the end of this document. If you do not wish to receive future commercial communications from us by e-mail, simply follow the unsubscribe instructions contained within the e-mail. If you've registered on any part of the Website, please use the mechanism on the Website that allows you to change or update your member preferences or information, if available, to keep all such date accurate and up-to-date. 

Otherwise, click here to be removed from all Specialist Media mailing lists. 

We also allow access to our database by third parties that provide us with services, such as technical maintenance or forums and in future job search software, but only for the purpose of and to the extent necessary to provide those services. And if you choose to purchase items through features on the Website, we may forward your information to third parties for services such as credit card processing and order fulfilment. There are also times when you provide information about yourself to us in areas of the site that may be managed or participated in by third parties, such as auction services or shopping areas. In such cases, the information may be used by us and by such third party(ies), each pursuant to its own policies. 

We may also provide your information to our advertisers, so that they can serve ads to you that meet your needs or match your interests. We may also provide access to our database in order to cooperate with official investigations or legal proceedings, including, for example, in response to subpoenas, search warrants, court orders, or other legal process. 

In addition, we reserve the right to use the information we collect about your computer, which may at times be able to identify you, for any lawful business purpose, including without limitation to help diagnose problems with our servers, to gather broad demographic information, and to otherwise administer our Website. 

While your personally identifying information is protected as outlined above, we reserve the right to use, transfer, sell, and share aggregated, anonymous data about our users as a group for any business purpose, such as analyzing usage trends and seeking compatible advertisers and partners. 

In addition, as our business changes, we may buy or sell various assets. In the event all or a portion of the assets owned or controlled by Service Provider, its parent or any subsidiary or affiliated entity are sold, assigned, transferred or acquired by another company, the information from and/or about our Website users may be among the transferred assets. 

3\. COOKIES   
Cookies: We may use a feature of your browser called a cookie to assign your computer a 'User ID'. Cookies contain information by which SM can identify your computer to our servers. You may configure your browser so that you are notified before a cookie is downloaded or so that your browser does not accept cookies. SM may use information contained in cookies to make assumptions about the user of the computer and to provide users of that computer with focused advertising that SM believes may be of interest, based on that information. In some cases a web page might contain more than one cookie, the information gathered from these different cookies are used to build statistical and demographical information which does not identify you personally to advertisers and other third parties for marketing, promotional purposes. 

To disable your cookies, please refer to the help menu within your Internet browser. However, if you set your browser to refuse cookies, some portions of the Website may not function properly. 

Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may also use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the Website. These vendors may use cookies, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other data. The use of cookies, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and SM disclaims all liability in connection therewith. 

4\. INFORMATION SECURITY AND NOTIFICATION   
Because no data transmission over the Internet is completely secure, and no system of physical or electronic security is impenetrable, SM can not guarantee the security of the information you send to us or the security of our servers or databases, and by using the Website you agree to assume all risk in connection with the information sent to us or collected by us when you use the Website. In the unlikely event that we believe that the security of your information in our possession or control may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you. If notification is appropriate, we may notify you by e-mail (provided we have your e-mail address). 

5\. MINORS AND PARENTS   
This Website is not intended for use by children, especially those under age 13. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information or use our public discussion areas, forums and chats. Minors between the ages of 13 and 17 must get the permission of their parent(s) or legal guardian(s) before making purchases, including subscriptions, on this site. If your children disclose information about themselves in publicly accessible areas of the Website, they may get unsolicited messages from other parties. Accordingly, you should tell them not to do so. If you're worried about your children's activities or their privacy on our site, we encourage you to contact our Privacy Policy Coordinator as described below. 

6\. PRIVACY POLICY COORDINATOR   
Click here for instructions to be removed from Service Provider's mailing lists. If you have any concerns or questions about any aspect of this policy, please feel free to contact our Privacy Policy Coordinator as follows: 

Privacy Policy Coordinator Specialist Media Pty Ltd. PO Box 6690 Gold Coast Mail Centre Qld 9726 Australia

Merge magazine is wholly owned by Specialist Press Pty Ltd.
